I've been in the digital marketing space for
about four years now and within that time frame
I've worked on a lot of different social media
pages and channels and I've always been able to
grow them pretty consistently but it hasn't been
until recently about the past six months or so
that I've noticed a couple key ingredients and
really just a formula for growing pages at a
pretty rapid and explosive rate. So that's some of
the things I'll be sharing today and this really
applies to Instagram and Facebook. So if you guys
do get some value from this video, if you guys
learn something or would really appreciate if you
guys could leave us a like and subscribe,
let's go ahead and hop right in. The first
tip is also the most important because it's the
foundation for all the other tips we'll be covering
today and that is consistency. You may have heard
that advice a thousand times but it seriously
is so important to be consistent because once you
have momentum it's important to keep that going. So
I recommend that you post every day or at least
every other day so that way you can keep
that top of mind awareness and keep your loyal followers
engaged.
So some of the things you can do to get
content ideas. The first thing you can do is use your
competitors and people who are in a similar space
to your advantage. So visit some of the pages that
you know who post similar content as yours or
in a similar space or look at relevant hashtags to
your business and see what's trending, what some
of the top posts are and get some creative
inspiration from them. One of the best things you
can do is actually use pages that are in
your similar space as yours
and get content from their page.
I mean this in a genuine way though. So let's say
you have a post from Elon Musk that I really like
and it's an inspirational quote that I want to
share with my own audience. What I'll do is I'll
post it on my own page and give them credit in
the description. So not only is I get a win because I'm
able to get some content from my own page
but they're also getting a win because they're getting
some extra exposure to my audience and they'll
get some followers from my page as well. Seriously
though you want to give credit to the respective
page because it sucks when it happens to you.
And people don't give you credit and it's honestly
just awkward when you DM them saying hey can you
give us credit. The second thing that you can do
is just google it and the reason I say that is
because if you just google up your industry
and then content ideas hundreds of articles will pop
up and you can just go to google images see
what some of the content ideas they have on there and
see what some other people have posted in the
past as well as there's usually long blog articles with
like 50 or 25 ideas that you
can kind of take creative inspiration from.
And then just apply that to your own page. People
typically look at content on pages for one of two
reasons and it's one is for education to learn
something and see something new or two is just
for entertainment. So what you want to do
is look at the analytics of your previous posts,
see what works, see what doesn't work
and then just model and replicate what works.
Tip number two is to start utilizing reels. Reels
is the best way to get massive organic reach and
it doesn't matter if you have five
followers or five hundred thousand followers on your
page because Instagram and Facebook are doing a
very good job of promoting this content across
all their platforms and the virality of this will
always be the potential virality of let's say a
static post. If you don't know how to post a
reel I actually made a video previously on how to make
a reel so you go ahead and check that out if
you guys want some information on how to go ahead and
do that. One of the best ways to get content
ideas for reels is to actually head over onto TikTok
and the reason being is because their algorithm and
just their content is so much better than the
content on their page. So it's really important to
have that in mind and it's really important to
be able to get your content ideas for reels. And so
I've been using the reels for a while and I've been
content creators over there have more or less
perfected the art of short form content. So a
great thing about actually making Instagram and Facebook
reels is that you might as well go ahead
and start uploading those videos onto TikTok as
well, just because it's the same concept, really.
It's still the same type of short form content,
short form videos, and they also have a creator
fund program over there. So once you hit
10,000 followers, you're able to actually monetize your
channel, which is really cool. What I'm about
to say does not really apply to local businesses,
social media, but let's say you're trying to grow
a theme page such as rap or business, for example.
If you want to grow a rap page and
you don't always have the time or capability to create
the video yourself, if you want to look at a viral
video or a trending video or just a video that you
like in general, and you want to download it and
upload it to your own page, it is generally okay
with most content creators as long as you tag
them. Tip number three is hashtags matter, and this
especially matters when you're getting a lot of people
to your channel. So if you're getting a lot
of people to your channel, you're getting your page
off the ground. And on static posts, I like to
use eight to 10 hashtags. On videos and reels, I
like to use six typically. And so the reason this
matters and the reason you want to keep it relevant
to the video or post is because let's say one of
your hashtags is investing and let's say it starts
to get traction, your post starts to get traction.
What it will do is two things. One is it
will put you on the explore page because they'll say,
they'll notice that, hey, people that typically,
like investing hashtag posts are liking your
posts, and they'll start promoting it to that
demographic of people. And the second thing is,
is they'll actually start pushing your photo or video
onto the homepage of people that don't even follow
you. So it's a great way to get some
extra exposure. And that's why you want to keep
it relevant to the post because if it's not,
it won't get pushed very far. You just
have to remember to be patient because using hashtags,
especially in the beginning, doesn't really seem like it's
worth it. But trust me, it is one of the
key factors to growing your page. Tip number four is
to be patient. If you're not, you're not going to
be able to get a lot of views. So don't
be afraid to use hashtags. And the second thing is,
don't upload watermarked videos. I don't know what
it is about the Instagram and Facebook algorithm,
but they do not like the TikTok logo and
the watermark on your videos. So what I've noticed
is because starting out is I would upload the
TikTok logos and videos that I uploaded on TikTok
just straight to the feed. And I was
like, why aren't these videos that are really good
getting no traction at all? So once I started
downloading them off of a website I use called
SnapTik, which is completely free. I use it for all
my videos. And I've been using it for a long
time. So I'm pretty sure it's pretty safe at
least. And I'll put it in the description. And
pretty much all you do is you just copy the
video link and then upload it on there and you just
download it. And I noticed that your
reach will get significantly higher without a watermark
on your videos. Tip number five is to invite
people to like your page. One of the coolest
features about Facebook where it's currently only available there
is if you have a video or a photo
that someone likes, you can go
to the reactions of that post.
And invite them to like your page. And you
can typically invite two to 300 people at a time.
But beware that you don't do more than that because
you'll end up like me and get banned from inviting
people for about 48 hours. That's how long I
was banned approximately. So it's a really cool feature
to go ahead and improve the speed of your
page growth. And I highly recommend that you do that.
Tip number six is to promote engagement
and followers via your descriptions of your videos
and posts. I like to ask people, what are
your thoughts? What are your opinions? Or what would
you choose? Like what would you do in
this situation? Ask people a question to promote
engagement in the comments. And the more comments
that you typically get typically goes with how
well the static post actually does. And then the same
thing for videos is I like to do, you know,
follow to join the team, follow to join
the movement or ask them, hey, like, like promote
engagement somehow, you know, that I like the
last advice at the end to promote watch time,
like, you know, follow to join the team, follow
to join the movement, for example. Or same thing as
a statics is what are your thoughts? What are
your thoughts? And then the last thing is to
be creative, try new ideas, try new tactics, try
whatever you can to just grow the page. And trust
me, if you just try out, be creative,
and constantly test out new strategies, it's a great
way to grow the page. And, and yeah, it's the
same thing with videos is I like to do either a
thought provoking question or a conversation starter as
the description, or like to do a call
to action to follow the page.
So I hope you guys enjoyed today's video. If
you did, please give us a like and subscribe.
Would really appreciate that. Hope you guys have a
great day. I'll catch you guys in the next one.